CV Altaf Shaikh

Address: E-103, Sunflower Enclave, Near Emad Tower, TP-85 Road, Fatehwadi, Sarkhej

Road, Ahmedabad, Gujarat - 380055

Mobile Number: 8401071024 / 9537644358

Email: altafshaikh2001@gmail.com

PROFILE

An organised, results-oriented individual with a long excellent track record working within Recruitment Process Outsourcing at all levels mainly in the UK including Waste Management, Financial Services, Banking, IT Services, Supply Chain Management, Rec to Rec, Digital Marketing, Engineering, Healthcare, Property & Construction, etc. I am particularly good at building and already have great relations within these sector. Good comm skills, relationship-building and influencing skills; competent in building Client relationships which inspire confidence and loyalty. A highly efficient individual with extensive team leadership experience, able to adapt well to new environments and learn new processes quickly to achieve outstanding results. Strong ability to multi-task and priorities, and able to organise, train and monitor teams.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Technomine – True Outsourcing Excellence Process Manager

Sep 2012 – Present Apr 2015 – Present

Current Client Duties Involved (but not limited to):

- Daily Placement tab check on CRM i.e., Creating invoice on same date it was created, sending invoice to Clients on candidates start date after authorisation from MD and chasing payment on the next day of due date & sending Polite reminders.
- Daily Vacancy check on CRM twice a day Morning & Evening and Updating Company's Wordpress with any new Vacancies.
- Updating CRM with Outlook plugin as and when Candidates Send CV.
- Updating CRM with any unsubscribes from either monthly mailer / nudge mailer by email received from all the Consultants.
- Updating CRM with removing undelivered mobile number.
- CV Prepping/formatting as and when received.
- Weekly Revenue & Placement Leader board update.
- Wednesday Holiday update
- Registering Holiday bookings to Holiday planner worksheet as and when requested by consultants
- Rotating Vacancies on both Wordpress on specific date of every month.
- Candidates' postcode & City check on CRM on a regular interval.

Technomine Duties involved:

- Personally generating revenue of £500 per month & as a team roughly minimum £3000 per month.
- Managing a team of 5 members. (Highest managed 15 team members)
- Daily / Weekly / Monthly reports to all the Clients as per SLA (Service Level Agreement)
- Answering all the queries of the Clients.
- Creating Invoice & Payment chase as per agrees SLA for all the Clients.
- Managing attendance of the team members and booking holidays.
- Resolving issues of the Team members
- Training New Joinees & existing Team Members with any new Projects & CRMs.
- Acting as a mediator between the Client & the team members.

Achievements:

• Star Performer of the Month (Multiple occasions)

Key Responsibilities:

- Acting Assistant Manager Operations
- Team management.
- Working with a number of clients globally, mainly UK. Other areas covering Europe, Ireland, Middle East, US.
- Recruitment includes (CV Sourcing, Screening, Interviews, Placement, CV Formatting, Headhunting, Active Search Using Portals & Passive Search using LinkedIn Premium Account)
- Data Mapping (Populating MNCs Leads with Corporate Email Id Using Various tools & LinkedIn Premium Extensions)
- Report Daily, Monthly, Yearly.
- Attendance Management
- Training & Allocation of work to the team.
- Client Communication to manage the process swiftly.
- Invoicing, Payment Chase

Achievements:

Promising Manager of the Year 2014

Senior Recruitment Consultant

Sep 2012 - Nov 2013

Key Responsibilities:

- CV Sourcing
- Active as well as Passive Candidate search from different sources like job portals, LinkedIn, Client database like CRM Application, etc.
- CV Formatting
- Headhunting
- Candidate Pre-Screening
- Name Gathering, Data Mining, Lead Generating
- Client Account Handling
- Client Communication
- Handling Multiple clients at a time
- Generating Monthly Invoice
- Chasing Payments
- Passive Search using different tools like Copernic, Recruitment Bar, etc.
- End to End recruitment
- Contract and Perm Recruitment
- Business Development Activities
- Preparing different kinds of weekly/monthly reports

Achievements:

Consistent Performer of Year 2013

IMS People (Interactive Manpower Solutions) Senior Recruitment Consultant

Jul 2010 - Aug 2012 Jan 2012 - Aug 2012

Key Responsibilities:

- CV Sourcing
- Active as well as Passive Candidate search from different sources like job portals, LinkedIn, Client database like CRM Application, etc.
- CV Formatting
- Headhunting
- Candidate Pre-Screening
- Name Gathering, Data Mining, Lead Generating
- Client Account Handling
- Client Communication

- Handling Multiple clients at a time
- Passive Search using different tools like Copernic, Recruitment Bar, etc.
- End to End recruitment
- Preparing different kinds of weekly/monthly reports

Achievements:

• Star Performer of the Month (multiple occasions)

Recruitment Consultant

Jul 2010 - Dec 2011

Key Responsibilities:

- Sourcing candidates from different job portals like Monster, Jobsite, LinkedIn, etc.
- Scanning and short listing the most suitable CVs for the position.
- Conducting telephonic interview of the shortlisted candidates.
- Emailing details of client to shortlisted candidate.
- CV Preparing
- Scheduling and organizing final interview of the shortlisted candidates.
- Ensuring that proper Follow up of selected candidates happens till their start with the firm.
- Getting background/reference checks conducted prior/post to joining.(Educational, Employment)
- Maintaining Database of candidates appeared, interviewed, selected etc.
- Preparing various MIS reports related to the entire Recruitment and Selection process

Achievements:

Star Performer of the Month (multiple occasions)

Etech Inc. (Effective Teleservices Limited) Quality Auditor and Telesales Representative

Feb 2008 - Jul 2010

Key Responsibilities:

- Worked as Quality auditor for 2 years and 3 months.
- Auditing Calls & Chats for agents of US & UK campaign.
- Calibrating with clients and operations team.
- Providing weekly & monthly reports to operations.
- Coaching agent for improvement of sales.
- Providing coaching to new joiners.
- Later on moved to operations as Telesales Representative in UK campaign. Worked as TSR for 2 months.

Achievements:

- Performer of the Month (multiple occasions)
- Successfully cleared Beginners Level in Excel.

Metrix Healthcare Pvt. Ltd. (Pharma distributors) Sales Coordinator

Jan 2007 - Feb 2008

Key Responsibilities:

 Creating New Client through phone, Managing current clients, Collecting orders from existing clients, supplying ordered medicines to client. Dispatching sample pack of medicines to new clients. Regular interaction and follow up with new & existing clients. Additional administrative work like booking hotels & rail tickets on client visit.

Al Suwaid General Transport LLC, Abu Dhabi – UAE (Transport & Logistics) Aug 2004 – Nov 2006 General Accountant

Key Responsibilities:

- Managing Accounts for the company
- Calling Existing and New customer for Rental of Heavy Vehicles like Bulldozer, Shovel (Wheel Loader),

_				
()	ra	ne.	Ο.	1
u	а	IIC.		LL.

- Distributing Salaries to Employees.
- Generating monthly bills for clients.
- Petty Cash Handling.
- Faxing Monthly report at Head office Dubai.
- Handling Monthly Income and Expenditure
- Occasional Site visit for Vehicle Inspection.

EDUCATION:

DT Law College, Gujarat University	2002 – 2004	
LLB – 4 semesters cleared (Incomplete)		
Ahmedabad Arts & Commerce College, Gujarat University	1999 – 2002	
Bachelor of Commerce, Accountancy & Statistics		
Vasant Higher Secondary School	1997 – 1999	
HSC – Commerce		
Gyandeep Higher Secondary School	1996 – 1997	
SSC		

SKILLS:

Top Skills

- CV formatting / Prepping
- Recruiting
- Sourcing
- Client Communication

Languages

- English
- Hindi
- Gujarati
- Urdu Reading
- Arabic Reading

Honors-Awards

- Promising Manager of the Year 2014
- Consistent Performer of Year 2013
- Start Performer of the Month (Multiple times)
- Certificate in Computing from IGNOU